Hello everyone, welcome to another
great lesson with us here at English Pod.
My name is Marco
and I'm Erica and today
We're going to be talking about
an ER and emergency room exactly
we're bringing you our very
own ER drama here at English Pod
Yeah, doctor shows are very popular with
people medical terms and all that stuff
Yeah, so we're going to
teach you some words that you
might hear commonly in
medical shows on TV or in movies
This is really common
language in television
or even at a hospital,
right? Well, yeah
But but let's hope our
listeners don't have to face this.
Okay, so let's preview some
words in vocabulary preview
vocabulary preview
All right, so what's our first word?
Okay, the first word is CPR
CPR CPR so that's pretty easy.
What does that mean?
Well, it's short for cardio
pulmonary resuscitation. Okay
That needs anything to you.
Well cardio is related to the heart
Pulmonary refers to the
lungs. Yep resuscitation
means to come back to
life. Yes, so basically CPR is
You know when someone stops
breathing? Mm-hmm. You put your mouth on
their mouth and you breathe inside
their lungs. Okay to give them air
Yeah, okay, so CPR that's CPR. Okay,
so let's take a look at our next word BP
BP so BP is short for blood
pressure blood pressure.
That's just the way that doctors
use it in the emergency room
Exactly pretty simple. Okay,
so blood pressure and our last
word acute respiratory
failure a cute respiratory failure
So what is that exactly?
That sounds complicated?
Basically, it's really serious
that you stop breathing.
You stop breathing. Yeah, okay
So if you go into acute
respiratory failure than
the doctor or somebody
has to perform CPR, right?
All right. Cool. Okay, so we've so we've
previewed these three great words now
Let's listen to our
dialogue for the first time.
It's gonna be really fast and you're
gonna have a lot of drama in it
So don't worry if you
don't understand everything.
Yeah, we're gonna come back and
teach you some of the important language
How are you doctor?
My poor little Frankie.
He's just stopped
breathing. Oh my gosh.
Help me I tried to perform
CPR, but I just I don't
know if I could get
any air into his lungs. Oh
Ellen get him hook up to a
monitor somebody page doctor.
How's her get the
patient hold still?
I can't get a pulse
Okay, he's on the monitor his BP's falling.
He's flatlining. Oh
Someone get her out of here
get me the defibrillator. Okay, clear
Again clear
Come on, Jim, and I'm
not letting go of you clear
About a pulse. Okay, what's
happening patient is in acute
respiratory failure. I think
we're going to have to innovate
All right tubes in bagging
somebody giving 10
cc shot of adrenaline.
Let's go people move move
Doctor oh, thank God. How is he?
We've managed to stabilize Frankie,
but he's not out of the woods yet
He's still in critical condition
We're moving him to
intensive care, but doctor.
Just do whatever it takes. I just
want my little Frankie to be okay
I couldn't imagine life
without my little hamster
Wow so much drama
over a little hamster.
Yeah a little pet a
little pet a little hamster
Well, you know what I
can relate to this owner and
I'm gonna tell you a little
bit more about that later
Yeah, I know you have a really good
story about this. Yeah, but in the meantime
Let's look at some great
language in language takeaway
Language takeaway
All right, so let's take
a look at our first word
Intubate intubates intubate
Intubates, so this is a
medical procedure exactly
When a patient can't breathe properly
sometimes the doctor takes a long tube
And puts it into their
mouth and down their pipes.
I guess down their breathing tube
right so that they can breathe better
Okay, so that's to intubate. Yes.
Okay, so once they've intubated the patient
They start to bag him.
Yeah bag him bag him.
Does that mean they
like put a bag over the
So there's a bag
attached to this intubation
tube and you squeeze it
to put air into the lungs
Okay, so you squeeze
this bag and it puts air yeah
through the tube. I think
this is just medical slang
Yeah, I guess backhand. Yeah,
but you hear all the time on TV.
So it's important our
listeners know it. Okay
Let's look at our next word
critical condition critical
condition critical condition
the patients in critical condition
This condition means it's serious
right if a patient is in critical condition
They're either really
really hurt or really
really sick and they could
die pretty soon. Okay
So you don't want to
be in critical condition.
No, let's take a look
at our next word
Stabilize stabilize
So when the doctors stabilize a patient
they take that patient out of danger
Exactly when a patient is stabilized
They probably won't die in five
minutes. Okay, but they could
still be really sick. They could
be in critical condition, right?
But it's under control exactly.
Okay. Yeah, stabilize
Let's look at our last word.
I see you I see you I see you
Intensive care units. Okay. That's
what it means intensive care unit. Yep.
So that's the place where patients
who are in critical condition are taken
Right, so what's the difference
between an ICU and a regular room?
Well, I don't know.
I've never been in one
But I think like patients are monitored
Regularly and I think there's
you know, maybe more
maybe there are more
nurses and fewer patients
There's just a higher level of care
a higher level of care. Yeah. Okay
Okay, so it's time
for us to listen to our
dialogue again now
try to catch all of these
Medical terms that we
just talked about and
then we'll come back
and explain a few phrases
Help are you a doctor?
My poor little Frankie.
He's just stop breathing. Oh my
gosh. Help me. I tried to perform CPR
But I just I don't know if I could get
in the air into his lungs. I hope for a key
Ellen get him hook up to a
monitor somebody page doctor.
How's her get the
patient hold still?
I can't get a pulse
Okay, he's on the monitor his BP's falling.
He's flatlining. No
Doctor does something
Someone get her out of here.
Get me the defibrillator. Okay clear
Again clear
Come on, damn it.
I'm not letting go of you clear
I've got a pulse. Okay. What's
happening the patient is in acute
respiratory failure. I think
we're going to have to innovate
All right tubes in bag
him somebody giving 10
cc's shot of adrenaline.
Let's go people move move
Doctor. Oh, thank god. How is he?
We've managed to stabilize
Frankie, but he's not out
of the woods yet. He's
still in critical condition
We're moving him to
intensive care, but doctor
Just do whatever it takes. I just
want my little Frankie to be okay.
I couldn't imagine life
without my little hamster
Okay, so there are some really good
phrasal verbs in this dialogue. Yeah
Couple of good phrasal
verbs. Okay, so let's take a
look at these phrasal
verbs in putting it together
Putting it together
All right, so what's our first
phrasal verb today hook up hook up?
So to hook up so when we when
we talk about hooking something up
We are usually talking
about electronics right Marco.
Yeah, you usually hook up
your TV or your computer
So why don't we listen to some examples
of how we would use hook up example one?
I finally got an Nintendo Wii come
on help me hook it up to the TV
Example two I
Don't know how to hook up this
new DVD player. Can you help me?
Example three
I Just hooked up my new HD TV
want to come over and watch a movie
Great, so you can see that
there are a few different
Variations of this pattern here
with the word hook up because it's a
phrasal verb exactly and I think the
same patterns can apply to our next
phrasal verb
Hold still hold still hold still hold still
So the doctor needed
the patient to hold
still right to stop moving
stop moving exactly
Okay, let's listen to some more
examples of hold still because again
It's a really great phrasal verb
that you can change up a little bit
Example one
If you don't hold still I can't see
if you have something in your eye
Example two
Hold still while she cuts your hair
or else she might make a mistake
Example three
Hold still you have a B on your back
Okay, hold still great word yep
All right, one final phrase for you out of
the woods out of the woods out of the woods
So when someone's out of the
woods they're free from danger.
Uh-huh safety safe. Yeah,
I guess it's kind of a saying
Yeah, I'm out of the
woods. I'm free. I'm safe.
I guess there are two
variants of this phrase
We can say I'm out of the
woods or we're out of the woods
or I guess we're not out of
the woods. Yes. Uh-huh. So
Okay, out of the woods. Mm-hmm.
Okay, so now it's time for us
to listen to our dialogue again
And when we come back Eric is
gonna tell us about her ER story
Help are you doctor?
I put a little Frankie.
He's just stopped breathing.
Oh my gosh. Help me
I tried to perform CPR,
but I just I don't know
if I could get any air
into his lungs Oh, Frankie
Ellen get him hooked up to a
monitor somebody page doctor.
How's her get the
patient hold still?
I can't get a pulse
Okay, he's on the monitor his BP's falling.
He's flatlining
Someone get her out of here
get me the defibrillator. Okay clear
Again clear
Come on, damn it.
I'm not letting go of you clear
About a pulse. Okay. What's
happening patient is in acute
respiratory failure. I think
we're going to have to innovate
All right tubes in baggy
somebody give him 10 cc's
shut off adrenaline. Let's
go people move move
Doctor. Oh, thank god.
How is he? We've managed to
stabilize Frankie, but he's
not out of the woods yet
He's still in critical condition
We're moving him to intensive care,
but doctor. Just do whatever it takes
I just want my little
Frankie to be okay.
I couldn't imagine life
without my little hamster
Okay, Eric. So what happened?
What emergency did you have?
Well, it was with
my cat your cat
Yes, I had some people over for dinner
and it was maybe one 30 in the morning
And I went downstairs to let
them out and show them where the
taxis were and then I came up
and I saw that the cat was gone
And it turned out that the cat fell out
of the window fell out of the window.
Yeah, all right, but our
listeners have to know
What story or what floor
do you live on the 20th floor
the 20 is yeah, so this is
really dangerous, right?
That's really high up
So I went outside and I was
calling for my cat and I was like, Mr.
Finn, where are you? How
did you know he fell out?
I just knew. Yeah, yeah,
my mother's instinct.
I guess so and so he was
he was calling back to me and
So I picked him up
and brought him to the
house and then we had
to bring him to the vet
And it was you know two thirty
three in the morning at this time
and the vet was like not very
happy that we will come up on a bed
But that was a really good
emergency though. Yeah, so anyway
We brought him to the vet. He was
in critical condition for a couple of days
And then we had to keep him in
the vet the vets ICU for about a week
He broke his back.
He broke his two of his legs
Yeah, and so he was in the hospital
for three weeks and then at home
On bed rest for another three weeks
But now he's good as new.
Good as new. Yeah, he used
up one of his seven
lives. Yeah, nine nine. Yeah
I think maybe eight of his nine
days. He's only what got one left.
Yeah. Wow. That's
an interesting story
I guess that's the inspiration under
this dialogue exactly sometimes
We anglows really treats our
cats and our hamsters and our
dogs like there are children.
Yeah. Yeah. No, that's good
Well, I'm glad mr. Finn is okay, and he's
walking and good as new. Yep. Good as new
So maybe our users have some
stories about their pets being taken
to the hospital. I want to hear.
Yeah, that should be interesting
I've never had a pet actually
a break a leg or anything
So don't have any pet
stories this time, but we want
to hear what you think
so come to englishpot.
com Leave all your questions
and comments and your stories.
Yes, and we'll be there
to answer them well
guys Thanks for listening
and until next time